<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="rn_issues">
	<title>Known Issues</title>
	<shortdesc/>
	<conbody>
		<p>The following known issues exist in Eucalyptus 3.2 and its dependencies. Please contact
			Eucalyptus support for known workarounds to these issues.</p>
		<table>
			<tgroup cols="2">
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry>Issue</entry>
						<entry>Description</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>VMware Broker requires <codeph>eucalyptus</codeph> user to have write access to the <filepath>/etc/eucalyptus</filepath> directory
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/BROKER-9">BROKER-9</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>If the <codeph>eucalyptus</codeph> user does not have write access to the <filepath>/etc/eucalyptus</filepath>
							directory, the VMware Broker will stay in a <codeph>BROKEN</codeph> state, and <codeph>euca-configure-vmware</codeph>
							will fail. Run <codeph>chown -R eucalyptus:eucalyptus /etc/eucalyptus/</codeph> on the VMware Broker machine to ensure that
							the <codeph>eucalyptus</codeph> user owns the necessary files.</entry>					
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>User console requires upload of private key to access a Windows instance password
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-4293">EUCA-4293</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>Passwords for Windows instances are encrypted for a specified key pair. The user console requires that you
							upload the appropriate private key to access an instance password. <b>We strongly recommend against using
							this feature without HTTPS!</b> To access the instance password without uploading
							your private key, use <codeph>euca-get-password [instance id] -k [keyfile]</codeph> on the command line.</entry>					
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>User console cannot generate new Windows password on restarting a stopped instance
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-4291">EUCA-4291</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>The user console continues to display an old password after a Windows instance is stopped and 
							restarted. You must log out of the user console, log in again, and then generate a password, in order
							to log in to a Windows instance that has been stopped and restarted.</entry>					
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>User console hangs when launching an instance with large user data file 
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-4223">EUCA-4223</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>Launching an instance through the console may hang if the user data file is too big. Launch 
							instances on the command line if the user data file is larger than 16KB.</entry>					
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>A snapshot registered as an image must be deregistered twice to be fully removed 
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-4207">EUCA-4207</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>Running <codeph>deregister-image</codeph> does not initially delete the image record for a snapshot that 
							was registered as an image. You must run <codeph>deregister-image</codeph> twice to ensure the image is
							deleted.</entry>					
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>CC image caching does not work with some symlinks
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-4181">EUCA-4181</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>If <codeph>CC_IMAGE_PROXY_PATH</codeph> in <codeph>eucalyptus.conf</codeph> is set to a symlink, CC image caching may not work. 
							Ensure the symlink is placed in a path that is readable by the 'eucalyptus' user.</entry>					
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>The reporting feature in the Eucalyptus Administrator Console show no metrics. 
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-4168">EUCA-4168</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>This occurs only if you run a report that includes the current date. The metrics that
							show no data are: <uicontrol>CpuUsage%</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Net Total In/Out</uicontrol>,
							<uicontrol>Disk R/W</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Disk IOPS R/W</uicontrol>, and  <uicontrol>DiskTime</uicontrol>. For a
							workaround, use the CLI command, <apiname>eureport-generate-report</apiname>, to run reports
							from the Cloud Controller for a time period that includes the current date. You can also use
							the Eucalyptus Administrator Console and move the end date up the previous day.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>The <codeph>euca-describe-bundle-tasks</codeph> command does not keep task status after task completes
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-4140">EUCA-4140</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>When bundling a Windows instance, the task is removed from the task list as soon as the bundle completes, so euca-describe-bundle-tasks never shows a 'complete' status.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Attempts to create an instance from an uncached image stay pending indefinitely 
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-4112">EUCA-4112</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>If the cluster controller image cache is set to zero, attempts to create an instance from an uncached image
							will remain pending indefinitely. To prevent images being cached, remove the <codeph>CC_IMAGE_PROXY</codeph> line
							from <filepath>eucalyptus.conf</filepath>.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>[error:0290] message printed on upgrade
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-4027">EUCA-4027</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>The Eucalyptus upgrade process requires a large number of file descriptors, and an error may occur if <codeph>ulimit</codeph> is not 
							set to an appropriate value. To avoid this error, set <codeph>ulimit -n 5000</codeph> before upgrading Eucalyptus. 
							This error is not an indication of a failed upgrade.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Unable to start stopped instances after upgrade
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-4026">EUCA-4026</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>Eucalyptus 3.2 manages ISCSI targets in a different way to previous versions. The first attempt to start any stopped instances 
							relying on <codeph>iscsiadm</codeph> will fail, but the issue is resolved during cleanup so subsequent requests for that instance will work.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Capacity report shows unordered list of VM types
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-3707">EUCA-3707</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>When running a capacity report, the VM types are not ordered from smallest to largest instance type when displayed at the cloud or AZ property level.</entry>
					</row>
<!--these are issues carried over...discuss-->
					<row>
						<entry>Quota limiting run instances against availabilityzone resource does not work
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-3614">EUCA-3614</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>A policy which limits the number of instances which can be run within an availability zone has no effect.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>euca-describe-nodes does not return consistent results
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-3456">EUCA-3456</xref>)</entry>                              
						<entry>The output of euca-describe-nodes is not consistent.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>ENABLED CC have two NAT rules about 169.254.169.254
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-3440">EUCA-3440</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>In HA Mode, ENABLED CC can get into a state where it reports both ENABLED and DISABLED CLC in iptables for the metadata service.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>euca-start-instances does not return correct information
 							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-3311">EUCA-3311</xref>)</entry>                               
						<entry>euca-start-instances only returns the instance identifier and does not return the previous or the current state of the instance.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Walrus does not failover in HA if eucalyptus-cloud process is forcibly killed on primary
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-3202">EUCA-3202</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>If the eucalyptus-cloud process is forcibly terminated (kill -9) on the primary Walrus, failover to the secondary Walrus is not automatically triggered.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>euca-create-image from ebs backed instance fails, returns 0
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-1333">EUCA-1333</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>euca-create-image is currently unsupported.</entry>
					</row>
					
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
	</conbody>
</concept>
