<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept outputclass="docs one-sidebar sidebar-first" id="access_mapping_identities">
	<title>Identity Mapping</title>
 <shortdesc></shortdesc>
 <conbody>
 	<p>Identities in LDAP/AD are organized differently from the identity structure in Eucalyptus. So
 		a transformation is required to map LDAP/AD identities into Eucalyptus.</p>
 	
 	<p>The following image shows a simple scheme of how the mapping works. In this scheme, the user
 		groups in LDAP tree are partitioned into two sets. Each set is mapped into one separate account. Group 1, 2 and 3 are mapped to Account 1 and Group 4 and 5 are mapped to Account 2. As the result, all users in Group 1, 2 and 3 will be in Account 1, and all users in Group 4 and 5 will be in Account 2.</p>
 	
 	<image href="images/ldap_map.png" alt="mapping LDAP to Eucalyptus" align="center"/>
 	
 	<p>To summarize the mapping method:</p>
 	<ol>
 		<li>Pick user groups from LDAP/AD and combine them into different accounts. There are two ways of doing this:
 			<ul>	
 				<li>Use something called accounting groups. Account groups are essentially groups of groups. Each accounting group contains multiple user groups in LDAP/AD. Then each accounting group maps to an account in Eucalyptus.</li>
 				<li>Manually partition groups into accounts. Each group partition maps to an account.</li>
 			</ul>
 		</li>
 		<li>Once the accounts are defined (by accounting groups or group partitions), all the LDAP/AD user groups will be mapped into Eucalyptus groups within specific accounts; and LDAP/AD users will be mapped into Eucalyptus users. You also have options to filter the groups and users to be imported into Eucalyptus.</li>
 	</ol>
 	<p>Note that each group can be mapped into multiple accounts. But understand that Eucalyptus accounts are separate name spaces. So for groups and users that are mapped into different accounts, their information (name, attributes, etc) will be duplicated in different accounts. And duplicated users will have separate credentials in different accounts. For example, Group 1 may map to both Account 1 and Account 2. Say user A belongs to Group 1. Then Account 1 will have user A and Account 2 will also have user A. User A in Account 1 and user A in Account 2 will have different credentials, policies, etc., but the same user information.</p>
 	
 	<note>Currently, there is not a way to map individual users into an account. The mapping unit is LDAP user group.</note> 
 </conbody>
</concept>
