<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="configure_emc_vnx_multipath">
    <title>Configure EMC VNX Synchronous Snapshots</title>

    <shortdesc/>

    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>Setting the <codeph>&lt;partition&gt;.storage.enablesyncsnaps</codeph> property to
                    <codeph>true</codeph> will cause snapshots to be set synchronously during a
                    <codeph>euca-create-snapshot</codeph> operation. In this mode, the snapshot is
                created synchronously before the <codeph>euca-create-snapshot</codeph> command
                returns, while the copy and upload to Walrus still takes place asynchronously. This
                helps ensure that the <codeph>euca-create-snapshot</codeph> command returns quickly. </p>
            <p>If the CLC loses the connection with the SC or if the connection times out (the
                default timeout is 60 seconds), the SC will detect the connection has been closed
                and will mark the snapshot as failed and will clean up. This detection occurs after
                the VNX snapshot has been created, but before it initiates the thread that performs
                the asynchronous migration and transfer of the snapshot LUN to Walrus. When using
                synchronous snapshot mode, if the CLC returns an error to the user on the
                    <codeph>euca-create-snapshot</codeph> command then the snapshot will be marked
                as failed when listing snapshots using the <codeph>euca-describe-snapshots</codeph>
                command.</p>
            <p>To configure synchronous snapshots for an EMC VNX SAN:</p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd> Set the <codeph>&lt;partition&gt;.storage.enablesyncsnaps</codeph> property to
                        <codeph>true</codeph> : </cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock> euca-modify-property -p mypartition.storage.enablesyncsnaps=true</codeblock>
                </info>
            </step>
        </steps>
        <result> You have now successfully configured synchronous snapshots for your EMC VNX SAN
            installation. </result>
    </taskbody>
</task>
