<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="reporting_concepts">
 <title>Reporting Overview</title>
 <shortdesc></shortdesc>
 <conbody>
 	<p>Eucalyptus lets you generate reports to monitor cloud resource use. Each type of report is
 		for a specified time range. Eucalyptus supports the following report types:</p>
 	
 	<ul>
 		<li><b>Instance:</b> The instance report provides information about the amount, duration, and utilization of all running instances.</li>
 		<li><b>S3:</b> The S3 report provides information about the number of buckets and objects stored in Walrus. Empty buckets aren't reported.</li>
 		<li><b>Volume:</b> The volume report provides information about the amount, duration, and size of
 			all volumes in use.</li>
 		<li><b>Snapshot:</b> The snapshot report provides information about the amount, duration,
 			creation, and deletion of your cloud's snapshots.</li>
 		<li><b>Elastic IP:</b> The elastic IP report provides information about the lifeccyle of elastic
 			IPs in your cloud, including which user is using which IPs, which IPs are currently in use, and
 			how often and for how long does IP get allocated.</li>
 		<li><b>Capacity:</b> The capacity report provides succinct information about your cloud's
 			resources, including instances, storage, volumens, snapshots, and IPs.</li>
 		
 		
 		<!--<li><b>Storage:</b>Shows GB of storage used (max and GB-days) for volumes and snapshots during the date range specified. Display filters and grouping are the same as for instances.</li>
 			<li><b>Walrus:</b> Shows maximum buckets and objects used through Walrus during the date range specified. Display filters and grouping are available on a per-user or per-account basis.</li>-->
 	</ul>
 	
 	<p>You can generate reports in either CSV or HTML formats for use with external tools.</p>
 	
 	<p>If you want to use the CLC for your reports, see <xref href="reporting_tasks_clc.dita"/>.</p>
 	<p>If you want to use the data warehouse for your reports, see <xref
 		href="setting_up_dw.dita"/>.</p>
 	
 </conbody>
</concept>
