<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_xkz_f1k_vf">
 <title>Paths and Policy Scope</title>
 <conbody>
  <p>An optional path is useful to identify organizational differences between users or groups in
            the same account.  For example, consider the following two IAM ERNs:<ul
                id="ul_dcj_5bz_j3">
                <li>arn:aws:iam::sales:user/commercial/steve </li>
                <li>arn:aws:iam::sales:user/government/janet  </li>
            </ul>Both the user <i>steve</i> and the user <i>janet</i> are members of the sales
            department and <i>sales</i> account.  However, they sell to different customer
            segments.  This can be easily noted on the screen by placing them in different paths
            where the path names indicate which customer segment they sell to.   </p>
  <p>More importantly, paths are used to control the scope of permissions or policies. An
            administrator could be given permission to manage only the users and groups in a very
            specific subdivision of the <i>sales</i> account (department). In the following example,
            this policy could be used to allow a specific administrator the privilege to only manage
            users and groups created in the sales account with <i>commercial</i> in their paths. </p>
  <p/>
  <p>
   <image href="images/Paths-and-Policy-Scope.png" placement="break" id="image_wdz_r1k_vf"
    scale="60"/>
  </p>
  <p/>
  <p>
   <note>Creating a user in a path does not determine group membership.   Only explicit assignment
    to a group associates a user with a group.</note>
  </p>
  <p>It is recommended that you use separate accounts for resource accounting and chargeback, and
   that you use separate paths to limit permissions on resources.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
