<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="rn_issues">
	<title>Known Issues</title>
	<shortdesc/>
	<conbody>
		<p>The following known issues exist in Eucalyptus 3.1.1 and its dependencies. Please contact
			Eucalyptus support for known workarounds to these issues.</p>
		<table>
			<tgroup cols="2">
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry>Issue</entry>
						<entry>Description</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>CLC does not disable CC with invalid configuration
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-2313">EUCA-2313</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>When CC configuration is invalid and the CC is unable to launch instances, 
							the CLC does not mark the CC as DISABLED.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
                                                <entry> "Invalid content length null" message is seen in Walrus logs
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-1598">EUCA-1598</xref>)</entry>
                                                <entry> On a successful snapshot upload to Walrus, a spurious "Invalid content length null"
							message is seen in Walrus logs.</entry> 

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Error message for Web UI failure to add user to group is obscure
							(<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-1611">EUCA-1611</xref>)</entry>
						<entry> Error message on a failure to add user through the Web Dashboard is not descriptive enough and reads "failed to add users to selected groups"</entry>	
					</row>	
					<row>
						<entry>A long property key in the Web Dashboard is not visible
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-683">EUCA-683</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>Adding a property key to the Dashboard longer than around 20 chars 
							pushes the value fields outside of viewable area in Properties window </entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Column width should be resizable in main window
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-718">EUCA-718</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>Column width should be resizable in the main window of the Web UI Dashboard</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Should add a refresh button for the main pane
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-743">EUCA-743</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>The main pane of the Web Dashboard should have a refresh button</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Make any in the header a link back to UI landing page
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-747">EUCA-747</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>Common practice dictates that any logo in the header should link back to the Web Dashboard landing page</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Buttons enabled in Web UI when nothing is selected in list
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-670">EUCA-670</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>Buttons are spuriously enabled in the Web Dashboard when no account has been selected</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Walrus GetBucketAccessControlList response XML differs from S3
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-2292">EUCA-2292</xref>)</entry>                  
						<entry>When requesting an ACL for an object or bucket, Walrus currently returns an older 
							version of the XML structure that S3 used to use.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Path field in adding a new user should auto-populate
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-671">EUCA-671</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>When adding a new user, the user path field should auto populate to match
							username but with the "/" prepended</entry> 
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Quota policies can not be applied to groups so should be explicitly denied
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-1032">EUCA-1032</xref>)</entry>   
						<entry>Since quota policies only apply to groups, they should be denied when applied to users.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>The name of newly created resource is not restricted by IAM policy resource field
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-1019">EUCA-1019</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>IAM policy Resource field does not correctly restrict the name of the newly created resource</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Error message displayed in web GUI is not obvious enough
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-1610">EUCA-1610</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>Error messages should be displayed in a more obvious location than the bottom 
							left of the Web Dashboard window.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Web UI specifies button color but not button text color 
                                                        (<xref format='html' href="https://eucalyptus.atlassian.net/browse/EUCA-425">EUCA-425</xref>)</entry>
						<entry>The Web Dashboard specifies a whitish color for buttons without also
							specifying the color of the text that appears on buttons, essentially making
							the button white-on-white on systems with white-on-black themes. It should
							either specify both colors or neither.</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
	</conbody>
</concept>
