<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="task_hvf_tv4_b3">
    <title>Register Eucalyptus Services </title>
    <shortdesc/>
    <taskbody>
        <context><image href="images/frontend.png" placement="break" id="image_5qk_bw4_b3"
                scale="40"/>In this section of the lab you will register the Walrus, Cluster
            Controller, and Storage Controller services with the Cloud Controller. You will also
            register the Node Controller service with the Cluster Controller. </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>On the front-end host, register the Walrus service with the Cloud Controller. 
                    The Walrus public IP address is the same as the front-end public IP address. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># euca_conf –-register-walrus --partition walrus \
–-host &lt;walrus_public_IP> –-component walrus00  </codeblock>
                    <p>Answer <userinput>yes</userinput> when asked if you want to continue.  Enter
                        the root password of the Walrus host (front-end host) when prompted. The
                        root password should be <userinput>passwordNN</userinput> where <i>NN</i> is
                        the number of your student pod.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>On the front-end host, register the Cluster Controller service with the Cloud
                    Controller.  Name your cluster <i>cluster1</i>.   The Cluster Controller public
                    IP address is the same as the front-end host public IP address. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># euca_conf –-register-cluster --partition cluster1 \
–-host &lt;cluster_controller_public_IP> –-component cc00  </codeblock>
                    <p>Enter the root password of the Cluster Controller host (front-end host) when
                        prompted. The root password should be <userinput>passwordNN</userinput>
                        where <i>NN</i> is the number of your student pod.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>On the front-end host, register the Storage Controller with the Cloud
                    Controller.  The Storage Controller public IP address is the same as the
                    front-end public host IP address. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># euca_conf –-register-sc --partition cluster1 \
–-host &lt;storage_controller_public_IP> –-component sc00 </codeblock>
                    <p>Enter the root password of the Storage Controller host (front-end host) when
                        prompted. The root password should be <userinput>passwordNN</userinput>
                        where <i>NN</i> is the number of your student pod.</p>
                    <note>You will receive a message about the need to "choose a storage back end"
                        when you register the Storage Controller.   You will choose the storage back
                        end later in this lab exercise.</note>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>On the front-end host, register the Node Controller with the Cluster
                    Controller.  Use the Node Controller private IP address listed on your student
                    handout.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># euca_conf –-register-nodes=&lt;node_controller_private_IP>  </codeblock>
                    <p>Enter the root password of the Node Controller host when prompted. The root
                        password should be <userinput>passwordNN</userinput> where <i>NN</i> is the
                        number of your student pod.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>On the front-end host, verify that all Eucalyptus services are registered. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># euca_conf –-list-walruses
# euca_conf –-list-scs
# euca_conf –-list-clusters
# euca_conf –-list-nodes  </codeblock>
                    <note>The <systemoutput>STORAGECONTROLLER</systemoutput> service will report its
                        status as <systemoutput>BROKEN</systemoutput>.   This will change to
                            <systemoutput>ENABLED</systemoutput> once you configure a back-end
                        storage manager later in the lab.</note>
                </info>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
