<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="task_ctp_djh_b3">
    <title>Test default permissions for a normal user using euca2ools</title>
    <shortdesc/>
    <taskbody>
        <context>In this section of the lab you will use euca2ools to explore what you are able to
            do, and not able to do, using only the default user permissions.  In order to test
            euca2ools as the user <i>normal</i>, you will need to create a new Linux account and add
            the user <i>normal</i>'s cloud credentials to this account.</context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd><image href="images/desktop.png" id="image_4cz_r23_b3" scale="40"/>On the
                    Desktop, open an SSH session to the front-end host if an SSH session is not
                    currently open. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># ssh &lt;front_end_public_IP></codeblock>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>On the Debian desktop open an xterm window and use the Secure Copy command to
                    copy the credentials (<filepath>.zip</filepath> file) for the user <i>normal</i>
                    from the Debian desktop's <filepath>/root/Downloads</filepath> directory to the
                        <filepath>/tmp</filepath> directory on the front-end host. The credentials
                    were downloaded to a <filepath>.zip</filepath> file in an earlier lab exercise.)
                    The IP address and password of your front-end host is listed on your student
                    handout.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># scp &lt;front_end_public_IP>:/root/Downloads/euca2-normal-x509.zip /tmp</codeblock>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd><image href="images/frontend.png" id="image_3yx_qrn_p3" scale="40"/>On the
                    front-end host create a new Linux user account for the user <i>normal</i>.
                    Assign the Linux account the password <userinput>passwordNN</userinput>, where
                        <i>NN</i> is the number of the student pod that your were assigned.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># useradd -m normal
# passwd normal
# ls -a /home/normal</codeblock>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>On the front-end host, switch to the new account for the user <i>normal</i>.  </cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># su  -  normal
# whoami
# pwd</codeblock>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>While working as the user <i>normal</i>, create a
                        <filepath>/home/normal/.euca</filepath> directory and copy the credential
                    zip file from <filepath>/tmp</filepath> to the <filepath>.euca</filepath>
                    directory.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># mkdir .euca
# cd .euca
# cp /tmp/euca2-normal-x509.zip .
# ls</codeblock>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>While working as the user <i>normal</i>, unzip the zip file and force the
                    user's shell to read the <filepath>eucarc</filepath> file and set the EC2
                    environment variables.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># unzip euca2-normal-x509.zip
# ls
# source eucarc
# env | grep EC2</codeblock>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>While working as the user <i>normal</i>, use the
                        <cmdname>euca-describe-images</cmdname> command to list any existing images. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># euca-describe-images</codeblock>
                    <p>Were there any images listed? There should not have been.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>While working as the user <i>normal</i>, use the
                        <cmdname>euca-describe-groups</cmdname> command to list any existing
                    security groups. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># euca-describe-groups</codeblock>
                    <p>Were there any security groups listed? There should not have been.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>While working as the user <i>normal</i>, use euca-add-keypair to create a key
                    pair.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># euca-add-keypair normal</codeblock>
                    <p>Were you able to create a new key pair?</p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Return to working as the root user by exiting the Linux shell that is operating
                    as the user <i>normal</i>.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <codeblock># exit
# whoami</codeblock>
                </info>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
