<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="component_understanding_shared">
	<title>Plan Component Placement</title>
	<shortdesc>A Eucalyptus deployment is a set of cloud services (Cloud Controller and Walrus) and
		one or more clusters, each of which contains a Cluster Controller, a Storage Controller, an
		optional VMware Broker (located with the Cluster Controller), and one or more Node
		Controllers. </shortdesc>
	<prolog>
		<metadata>
			<keywords>
				<indexterm>components <indexterm>cloud</indexterm>
					<indexterm>cluster</indexterm>
					<indexterm>node</indexterm>
				</indexterm>
			</keywords>
		</metadata>
	</prolog>

	<conbody>
		<image href="../shared/images/euca-arch-extras-tiers.png" scale="75">
			<alt>Image displaying cloud, cluster, and node components</alt>
		</image>

		<section>
			<title>Cloud Components</title>
			<p>The main decision for cloud components is whether to install the Cloud Controller
				(CLC) and Walrus on the same server. If they are on the same server, they operate as
				separate web services within a single Java environment, and they use a fast-path for
				inter-service communication. If they are not on the same server, they use SOAP and
				REST to work together.</p>
			<p>Sometimes the key factor for cloud components is not performance, but server cost and
				data center configuration. If you only have one server available for the cloud, then
				you have to install the components on the same server.</p>
			<p>All components should be in the same data center. They use aggressive time-outs to
				maintain system responsiveness so separating them over a long-latency, lossy network
				link will not work.</p>
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>Cluster Components</title>
			<p>The Eucalyptus components deployed in the cluster level of a Eucalyptus deployment
				are the Cluster Controller (CC), Storage Controller (SC), and VMware Broker.</p>
			<note type="tip">The VMware Broker is available by subscription only. You do not need
				the VMware Broker unless you are using VMware hypervisor.</note>
			<note importance="deprecated">Support for VMWare features in Eucalyptus has been deprecated and will be removed in a future release.</note>
			<p>You can install all cluster components on a single machine, or you can distribute
				them on different machines. The choice of one or multiple machines is dictated by
				the demands of user workload in terms of external network utilization (CC) and EBS
				volume access (SC). </p>
			<p>Things to consider for CC placement:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>For Managed and Managed (No VLAN) modes, the CC physical machine becomes a
					software IP gateway between VM instances and the public network. Because of this
					software routing function, the physical server on which the CC is deployed
					should have fast, dedicated network access to both the NC network, and the
					public network. </li>
				<li>For Edge mode, the CC physical machine will not act as a software gateway.
					Network traffic will be limited to small control messages. </li>
				<li>In all cases, place the CC on a machine that has TCP/IP connectivity to the
					Eucalyptus front end servers and the NC servers in its cluster.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Things to consider for SC placement:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>The machine on which the SC is deployed must always have TCP/IP connectivity to
					the CLC. If you are a subscriber and use one of Eucalyptus’ provided SAN
					integration drivers, the SC must also have TCP/IP connectivity to the chosen SAN
					device. In this case, the SC only sends control messages to the SAN. </li>
				<li>If you do not configure a SAN, the SC requires only TCP/IP connectivity to the
					NCs in the cluster. The SC will use this TCP/IP connectivity to provide the NCs
					network access to the dynamic block volumes residing on the SC’s storage. SC
					storage should consist of a fast, reliable disk pool (either local file-system
					or block-attached storage) so that the SC can create and maintain volumes for
					the NCs. The capacity of the disk pool should be sufficient to provide the NCs
					with enough space to accommodate all dynamic block volumes requests from
					end-users</li>
			</ul>
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>Node Components</title>
			<p>The Node Controllers are the components that comprise the Eucalyptus back-end. All
				NCs must have network connectivity to whatever hosts their EBS volumes. This host is
				either a SAN or the SC.</p>
		</section>

	</conbody>
</concept>
