<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="console_configure_memcached">
    <title>Configure Memcached</title>
    <shortdesc>Memcached is configured by default for the eucaconsole service on a single host. 
        On multiple hosts (in a scaling group), it is required to run a central memcached, as outlined in the 
        procedure below.</shortdesc> 
    <taskbody>
        <prereq> This procedure assumes that the Eucalyptus Management Console package is installed.
            For instructions on installing the packages, see <xref
                href="console_install_intro.dita#console_install_intro"/>. <note>If there is just
                one Console server, the automatically configured memcached service is sufficient for
                use by the console. </note></prereq>
            <steps>
               <step>
                   <cmd>Turn off the default memcached on all the consoles by editing <codeph>/etc/init.d/eucaconsole</codeph> 
                   and set <codeph>MEMCACHED_FLAGS="NO"</codeph>. This would normally be handled by your cloud-init or cfn-init 
                   script from your launch configuration.</cmd></step>
                <step>
                <cmd>Set up a central memcache to ensure your memcached instance is available and
                    durable, we recommend running it within a scaling group of 1 and behind an ELB.
                    The ELB requires a listener for port 11211 and its DNS address would be used in
                    the cache.memory.url in the next step. </cmd>
            </step>
                <step>
                        <cmd>Configure the console.ini file to talk to the central memcached. This
                            is typically defined in an init script, such as the cloud.init, shell
                            script or cfn.init file. For example, the memcached socket in the cache memory 
                            URL should point to the port that memcached uses (11211) to listen:</cmd>
                        <info><codeblock>cache.memory.url = /var/run/eucaconsole/memcached.sock</codeblock><p>to</p>
                            <codeblock>cache.memory.url = [memcachedhost]:11211</codeblock>
                            <p>For example: <codeblock>cache.memory.url = 10.0.0.20:11211</codeblock></p></info>
               </step>
              
            </steps>
    </taskbody>
    <task id="console_configure_memcached_clear">
        <title>Restarting the Console</title>
        <shortdesc/>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>If you add shared images with Euca2ools, you can make them available to users sooner by 
                        restarting the console, which clears the cache (memcached). To do that, restart the service:</cmd>
                    <info>
                        <codeblock>servicectl restart eucaconsole</codeblock>
                    </info>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
</task>