<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="console_dashboard_navigation">
    <title>Navigate the Dashboard</title>
    <shortdesc> The dashboard is your starting point for using the Eucalyptus console. From the
        Dashboard, you can access landing pages for instances, scaling groups, storage items
        (volumes, and snapshots), IAM users and groups, and networking and security objects (key
        pairs, security groups, load balancers, and IP addresses). </shortdesc>
    <taskbody/>
    <task id="console_dashboard_basic_steps">
        <title>Basic Dashboard Navigation</title>
        <shortdesc>You can navigate to specific resource management dialogs in two ways: using the
            navigation bar at the left of the screen or clicking directly on a resource icon or
            count in the Dashboard screen.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>You can click directly on a resource, listed under a category grouped by an
                        icon at the left of the main console page to navigate directly to a resource
                        management landing page or back to the main console screen (dashboard). </cmd>
                    <info><image href="images/console_nav.jpg" scale="80"
                        alt="Eucalyptus Console Navigation Bar"/>
                    </info>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> You can also navigate to a resource management landing page by clicking directly
                        on a resource tile/icon or count in the main dashboard view. </cmd>
                    <info><image href="../user-guide/images/run_instance_console_1.jpg" scale="80"
                        alt="Eucalyptus Console Launch Instance"/>
                    </info>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> You can also move resource tiles to any position on the dashboard to better 
                    accommodate the resources you use most often. To do this, hold and drag tiles to 
                    a different location on the screen.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> You can also remove tiles if you do not wish to display them on the dashboard 
                        by clicking on the action icon (･･･) for the resource tile you
                        want to remove and select <uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> The dashboard shows resources in all availability zones by default. You
                        can filter by availability zone by selecting an availability zone from the
                            <uicontrol>Availability Zones</uicontrol> drop-down list box at the top
                        of the page. </cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="console_dashboard_images_steps">
        <title>Images</title>
        <shortdesc>As one of the resources not available for access from the dashboard, you can access 
            a list of images that are currently used by your cloud from a link on the left side navigation panel.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> From the left side navigation panel, click the <uicontrol>Images</uicontrol> icon 
                        (power symbol) to display the <uicontrol>Images</uicontrol> landing page. 
                    </cmd>
                    <info>The <uicontrol>Images</uicontrol> landing page allows you to view details about each of 
                        the images currently used in your cloud configurations.</info>
                </step>            
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
                <task id="console_dashboard_instances_steps">
        <title>Instances</title>
        <shortdesc>The dashboard allows you to see how many instances are running, stopped, and part of a scaling group; 
            and allows you to navigate to the <uicontrol>Instances</uicontrol> landing page and the <uicontrol>Scaling Groups</uicontrol> 
            landing page, respectively.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> Click the <uicontrol>Running Instances</uicontrol> icon (clouds with green check mark) 
                        or the <uicontrol>Stopped Instances</uicontrol> icon (cloud with red stop symbol) from 
                        the dashboard to display the <uicontrol>Instances</uicontrol> landing page. </cmd>

                </step>

                <step>
                    <cmd> You can launch a new instance by clicking the <uicontrol>LAUNCH INSTANCE</uicontrol> button 
                        beneath the Running instances icon to display the <uicontrol>Launch new instance</uicontrol> wizard. </cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> For additional information on completing that page, refer to the instructions provided in its Help content.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> From the dashboard, you can view details about the instances that are part of a 
                        scaling group by clicking on the number in the Instances in scaling groups tile or 
                        clicking the <uicontrol>Scaling groups</uicontrol> icon (cloud with up and down arrows). 
                    </cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    
    <task id="console_dashboard_cf_steps">
        <title>CloudFormation</title>
        <shortdesc>The dashboard allows you to see how many CloudFormation stacks are active and to access the
            <uicontrol>Stacks</uicontrol> landing page.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> Click the number in the Stacks tile or <uicontrol>Stacks</uicontrol> icon (cloud with lightning) 
                        from the dashboard to display the <uicontrol>Stacks</uicontrol> landing page. </cmd>
                    
                </step>
                
                <step>
                    <cmd> You can create a new stack by clicking <uicontrol>Create stack</uicontrol> 
                        beneath the Stacks icon to launch the <uicontrol>Create stack</uicontrol> wizard.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> For additional information on completing that page, refer to the instructions provided in its Help content.</cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="console_dashboard_network_steps">
        <title>Network and Security</title>
        <shortdesc>The dashboard allows you to see at a glance the number of security groups, load balancers, key
            pairs, and elastic IP addresses in your Eucalyptus cloud, and to navigate to management
            landing pages for each type of object.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Security groups</uicontrol> landing page, click the
                        <uicontrol>Security groups</uicontrol> icon (shield symbol).</cmd>
                    <info>You can create a new security group by clicking <uicontrol>Create
                        security group</uicontrol> beneath the Security groups 
                        icon to launch the <uicontrol>Create security group</uicontrol> wizard.</info>
                </step>
                
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Load balancers</uicontrol> landing page, click the
                        <uicontrol>Load balancers</uicontrol> icon (spokes with arrows). </cmd>
                    <info>You can create a new load balancer by clicking <uicontrol>Create load 
                        balancer</uicontrol> beneath the Load balancers icon to launch the 
                        <uicontrol>Create load balancer</uicontrol> wizard.</info>
                </step>
                
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Key Pairs</uicontrol> landing page, click the
                        <uicontrol>Key pairs</uicontrol> icon (key symbol). </cmd>
                    <info>You can create a new key pair by clicking <uicontrol>Create key
                        pair</uicontrol> beneath the Key pairs  icon to launch the 
                        <uicontrol>Create key pair</uicontrol> wizard.</info>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Elastic IPs</uicontrol> landing page, click the
                        <uicontrol>Elastic IPs</uicontrol> icon (cloud with IP addresses).</cmd>
                    <info>You can allocate elastic IP addresses from the cloud, then associate 
                        them with your instances by clicking <uicontrol>Allocate elastic IPs</uicontrol> 
                        beneath the Elastic IPs icon and follow the prompts to allocate elastic IP addresses.</info>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> For additional information on completing any of the creation steps, 
                        refer to the instructions provided in each of their respective Help content.</cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    
    <task id="console_dashboard_storage_steps">
        <title>Storage</title>
        <shortdesc>The dashboard allows you to see at a glance the number of volumes, snapshots, and buckets 
            in your Eucalyptus cloud, and to navigate to landing pages for each type of storage object.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Volumes</uicontrol> landing page, click the
                        <uicontrol>Volumes</uicontrol> icon (cloud with cylinder).</cmd>
                    <info>You can create a new volume by clicking <uicontrol>Create
                        volume</uicontrol> beneath the Volumes icon to launch the 
                        <uicontrol>Create new volume</uicontrol> wizard.</info>
                </step>
                
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Snapshots</uicontrol> landing page, click the
                        <uicontrol>Snapshots</uicontrol> icon (cloud with camera). </cmd>
                    <info>You can create a new snapshot by clicking <uicontrol>Create snapshot</uicontrol> 
                        beneath the Snapshots icon to launch the <uicontrol>Create new snapshot</uicontrol> wizard.</info>
                </step>
                
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Buckets</uicontrol> landing page, click the
                        <uicontrol>Buckets (S3)</uicontrol> icon (bucket symbol). </cmd>
                    <info>You can create a new bucket by clicking <uicontrol>Create bucket</uicontrol> 
                        beneath the Buckets icon to launch the <uicontrol>Create new bucket</uicontrol> wizard.</info>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> For additional information on completing any of the creation steps, 
                        refer to the instructions provided in each of their respective Help content.</cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="console_dashboard_scaling_groups_steps">
        <title>Auto Scaling</title>
        <shortdesc>The Auto Scaling category consists of scaling groups and launch configurations. 
            The dashboard allows you to see how many scaling groups are configured 
            and to navigate to the <uicontrol>Scaling groups</uicontrol> landing page.</shortdesc>
                <taskbody>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <cmd> From the dashboard, click on the number in the Instances in scaling groups tile or 
                                click the <uicontrol>Scaling groups</uicontrol> icon (cloud with up and down arrows) 
                                to display the <uicontrol>Scaling groups</uicontrol> landing page. </cmd>
                             </step>
                        <step>
                            <cmd> You can create a new scaling group by clicking <uicontrol>Create
                                scaling group</uicontrol> beneath the Scaling groups icon to launch 
                                the <uicontrol>Create scaling group</uicontrol> wizard.</cmd>
                            <info>For additional information on completing that page, refer to the instructions 
                                provided in its Help content.</info>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <cmd> As one of the resources not available for access from the dashboard, you can access 
                                a list of launch configurations by clicking on the <uicontrol>Launch configurations</uicontrol> 
                                link on the left side navigation panel under the Auto Scaling category.</cmd>
                        </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
   
    <task id="console_dashboard_cw_steps">
        <title>CloudWatch</title>
        <shortdesc>The CloudWatch category is used for monitoring purposes and consists of alarms and metrics. 
            The dashboard allows you to see how many alarms are in alarm state and to navigate to the 
            <uicontrol>Alarms</uicontrol> landing page.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> From the dashboard, click on the number in the Alarms in alarm state tile 
                        or <uicontrol>Alarms</uicontrol> icon (bell symbol) to display the 
                        <uicontrol>Alarms</uicontrol> landing page. </cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> A metric must be selected before you can create an alarm. This is achieved 
                        by creating an alarm from a Metrics page of the monitoring tab on any resource's 
                        detail page, or from the Metrics landing page. </cmd>
               
                    </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> As one of the resources not available for access from the dashboard, you can access 
                        a list of metrics by clicking on the <uicontrol>Metrics</uicontrol> 
                        link on the left side navigation panel under the CloudWatch category.</cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    
    <task id="console_dashboard_iam_steps">
        <title>Identity and Access</title>
        <shortdesc>If you are the administrator of your Eucalyptus cloud, the dashboard allows you to 
            see at a glance the number of users, groups, and roles currently configured; and to navigate 
            to the landing pages for each type of Identity and Access Management (IAM) object.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Users</uicontrol> landing page, click the
                        <uicontrol>Users</uicontrol> icon (outline of a person).</cmd>
                    <info>You can create a new user by clicking <uicontrol>Create
                        users</uicontrol> beneath the Users icon to launch the 
                        <uicontrol>Create new users</uicontrol> wizard.</info>
                </step>
                
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Groups</uicontrol> landing page, click the
                        <uicontrol>Groups</uicontrol> icon (multiple persons symbol). </cmd>
                    <info>You can create a new group by clicking <uicontrol>Create group</uicontrol> 
                        beneath the Groups icon to launch the <uicontrol>Create new group</uicontrol> wizard.</info>
                </step>
                
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Roles</uicontrol> landing page, click the
                        <uicontrol>Roles</uicontrol> icon (photo badge symbol). </cmd>
                    <info>You can create a new role by clicking <uicontrol>Create role</uicontrol> 
                        beneath the Roles icon to launch the <uicontrol>Create new role</uicontrol> wizard.</info>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> For additional information on completing any of the creation steps, 
                        refer to the instructions provided in each of their respective Help content.</cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
        
    
    <task id="console_dashboard_misc_steps">
        <title>Miscellaneous Console Functions</title>
        <shortdesc>Clicking on your account ID in the upper-right corner of the console window
            displays a drop-down menu showing options to get help from the Eucalyptus support, 
            manage your credentials, get information about your cloud, and log out of the console. </shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To get help from the Eucalyptus support web site, select
                            <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol> from the drop-down menu.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To change your password or to generate a new set of access keys, 
                        select <uicontrol>Manage credentials</uicontrol> from the drop-down menu.</cmd>
                    <info>
                        <note>You can only change your Eucalyptus cloud password using the
                            Eucalyptus console. To change your AWS password, use the 
                            <xref
                                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/home?#security_credential"
                                scope="external" format="html">AWS Security Credentials page</xref>.</note>
                        <note>If generating new access keys, remember to save them as they are not stored 
                        anywhere on the cloud.</note>
                        <note>Please contact your cloud administrator to have them remove any old keys you are no longer using.</note>
                    </info>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To show the software version running your cloud, click
                            <uicontrol>About your cloud</uicontrol> from the drop-down menu.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To log out of the Eucalyptus console, select <uicontrol>Log
                            out</uicontrol> from the drop-down menu.</cmd>
                    <info>
                        <note>When logged into your AWS account, you can change your region by clicking
                            on the drop-down menu next to the account menu in the upper right corner of
                            the dashboard page. The Eucalyptus console will remember your last selected
                            region. </note>
                    </info>
                </step>
                
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    </task>
</task>
