<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="create_iam_accounts_ui_help_context">
    <title>Create Accounts</title>
    <shortdesc>Accounts are the highest entity for managing your users, groups and roles. 
        Each account owns and controls all the resources created under it and its set of assigned permissions.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody/>
    <task id="create_iam_accounts_ui_help_steps">
        <title>Create an account</title>
        <shortdesc>Add the details of your new account:</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>Type the name of your new account.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd>In the Add a user text field, type the name of each user to include in this
                        account and click <uicontrol>Add User</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                    <info>
                        <note importance="high">The admin user will be created for each account as part of the account creation, 
                            in addition to any other defined users. Because the admin user is created automatically, you do not have to do add it manually.</note>
                        </info>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd>Repeat for each user to include in the account.</cmd>   
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="console_account_detail_quotas">
        <title>Account Detail - Quotas</title>
        <shortdesc>Quotas lets you define limits on resources that users for this account is allowed
            to create. The quotas you define will be saved as a policy that will appear in the
            account's policy list.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>Expand the section for each service that you want to specify limits
                        for, and type in the maximum number of that resource in the text field.
                        Leaving a text field blank means no limit is assigned to that
                        resource.</cmd>
                </step>
                
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="create_account_ui_finish">
        <title>Save Your Work</title>
        <shortdesc/>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                
                <step>
                    <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Create Account</uicontrol> button to save your work, or
                        click the <uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol> button to cancel the
                        operation.</cmd>
                    <stepresult>Creating the account assigns it an ID, then generates and downloads a .csv file containing user information
                        along with passwords and access keys associated with each user.</stepresult>
                </step>
                </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
</task>