<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="console_dashboard_navigation">
    <title>Navigate the Dashboard</title>
    <shortdesc> The dashboard is your starting point for using the Eucalyptus console. From the
        Dashboard, you can access landing pages for instances, scaling groups, storage items (volumes, and
        snapshots), and networking and security objects (key pairs, security groups, and IP
        addresses). </shortdesc>
    <taskbody/>
    <task id="console_dashboard_basic_steps">
        <title>Basic Dashboard Navigation</title>
        <shortdesc>You can navigate to specific resource management dialogs in two ways: using the
            navigation icons at the top of the screen or clicking directly on a resource label or
            count in the Dashboard screen.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> You can click on one of the icons at the top of the dashboard to navigate
                        directly to a resource management screen or back to the main console screen.
                    </cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> You can also navigate to a resource management screen by clicking directly
                        on a resource label or count in the main dashboard window. </cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="console_dashboard_instances_steps">
        <title>Instances</title>
        <shortdesc>The <uicontrol>Instances</uicontrol> section allows you to see how many instances
            are running and access the Manage Instances screen.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> Click the <uicontrol>Running</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Stopped</uicontrol>
                        labels or counts in the <uicontrol>Instances</uicontrol> section of the
                        dashboard to display the <uicontrol>Manage Instances</uicontrol> screen. </cmd>
                    <info>
                        <note> Your initial view in the <uicontrol>Manage instances</uicontrol>
                            screen will be filtered by running or stopped instances, depending on
                            which label you clicked. To see all running and stopped instances, be
                            sure to change the the value in the search bar at the top of the
                                <uicontrol>Manage instances</uicontrol> screen. </note>
                    </info>
                </step>
                <step>

                    <cmd> You can filter the instances displayed on the dashboard by availability
                        zone by selecting an availability zone from the drop-down list in the
                        Instances section. </cmd>

                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> You can launch a new instance by clicking the <uicontrol>Launch
                            instance</uicontrol> link to display the <uicontrol>Create new
                            instance</uicontrol> screen. </cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="console_dashboard_scaling_groups_steps">
        <title>Scaling Groups</title>
        <shortdesc>The <uicontrol>In Scaling Groups</uicontrol> section allows you to see how many
            instances are running in scaling groups and access the Manage Scaling Groups
            screen.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> Click the <uicontrol>In Scaling Groups</uicontrol> label or count in the
                            <uicontrol>Instances</uicontrol> section of the dashboard to display the
                            <uicontrol>Manage Scaling Groups</uicontrol> screen. </cmd>

                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> You can filter the scaling groups displayed on the dashboard by
                        availability zone by selecting an availability zone from the drop-down list
                        in the Instances section. </cmd>
                </step>

            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="console_dashboard_storage_steps">
        <title>Storage</title>
        <shortdesc>The <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol> section allows you to see at a glance how many
            storage objects are running and access the various storage object management
            screens.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Manage Volumes</uicontrol> screen, click the
                            <uicontrol>Volumes</uicontrol> label or count.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Manage Snapshots</uicontrol> screen, click the
                            <uicontrol>Snapshots</uicontrol> label or count. </cmd>
                </step>

            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="console_dashboard_network_steps">
        <title>Network and Security</title>
        <shortdesc>The <uicontrol>Network and Security</uicontrol> section allows you to see at a
            glance the number of security groups, key pairs, and IP addresses in your Eucalyptus
            cloud, and to navigate to management screens for each type of object.</shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Manage Security Groups</uicontrol> screen, click
                        the <uicontrol>Security Groups</uicontrol> label or count.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Manage Key Pairs</uicontrol> screen, click the
                            <uicontrol>Key Pairs</uicontrol> label or count. </cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To access the <uicontrol>Manage IP Addresses</uicontrol> screen, click the
                            <uicontrol>IP Addresses</uicontrol> label or count.</cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="console_dashboard_misc_steps">
        <title>Miscellaneous Console Functions</title>
        <shortdesc>Clicking on your account ID in the upper-right corner of the console window
            displays a drop-down menu showing options to change your password, get help from the
            Eucalyptus Engage web site, get information about your cloud, and log out of the
            console. </shortdesc>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To get help from the Eucalyptus Engage community web site, select
                            <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol> from the drop-down menu.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To change your password, select <uicontrol>Change password</uicontrol>
                        from the drop-down menu.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To show a dialog box with information about your cloud, click
                            <uicontrol>About your cloud</uicontrol> from the drop-down menu.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> To log out of the Eucalyptus console, select <uicontrol>Log
                            out</uicontrol> from the drop-down menu.</cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>

</task>
