<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task outputclass="docs one-sidebar sidebar-first" id="setting_up_dns">
 <title>Configure DNS</title>
 <shortdesc></shortdesc>
 <taskbody>
 	<context>
 		<p>Eucalyptus provides a DNS service that you can configure to:</p>
 		<ul>
 		<li>Map instance IPs and Walrus bucket names to DNS host names</li>
 			<li>Enable DNS delegation to support transparent failover in HA mode</li>
 			</ul>
 			<p>The DNS service will automatically try to bind to port 53. If port 53 cannot be used, DNS will
 			be disabled. Typically, other system services like dnsmasq are configured to run on port 53. To use the Eucalyptus DNS service, you will need to disable these services.</p>
 		
 		
 	</context>
 	
 </taskbody>
	<task outputclass="docs one-sidebar sidebar-first" id="setting_up_dns_subd">
		<title>Configure the Subdomain</title>
		<taskbody>
			<context>
				<p>Before using the DNS service, configure the DNS sub domain name that you want Eucalyptus to handle as follows after the Eucalyptus Cloud Controller (CLC) has been started.</p>
				
				
			</context>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<cmd>Log in to the CLC (the primary CLC in an HA setup) and enter the following:</cmd>
					<info>
						<codeblock>euca-modify-property -p
system.dns.dnsdomain=&lt;eucadomain.yourdomain></codeblock>
					</info>
				</step>
			</steps>
		</taskbody>
	</task>
	<task outputclass="docs one-sidebar sidebar-first" id="setting_up_dns_map">
		<title>Turn on IP Mapping</title>
		<taskbody>
			<context>
				<p>To turn on mapping of instance IPs to DNS host names:</p>
				
				
			</context>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<cmd>Enter the following command on the CLC (the primary CLC in an HA setup):</cmd>
					<info>
						<codeblock>euca-modify-property -p bootstrap.webservices.use_instance_dns=true</codeblock>
						<p>When this option is enabled, public and private DNS entries are set up for each instance
							that is launched in Eucalyptus. This also enables virtual hosting for Walrus. Buckets created
							in Walrus can be accessed as hosts. For example, the bucket <codeph>mybucket</codeph> is
							accessible as <codeph>mybucket.walrus.eucadomain.yourdomain</codeph>.</p>
						<p>Instance IP addresses will be mapped as <codeph>euca-A.B.C.D.eucalyptus.&lt;subdomain></codeph>, where <codeph>A.B.C.D</codeph> is the IP address (or addresses) assigned to your instance. </p>
					</info>
				</step>
				<step>
					<cmd>If you wish to modify the subdomain that is reported as part of the instance DNS name, please enter the following command:</cmd>
					<info>
						<codeblock>euca-modify-property -p cloud.vmstate.instance_subdomain=&lt;custom-dns-subdomain></codeblock>
						<p>When this value is modified, the public and private DNS names reported for each instance will contain the specified custom DNS subdomain name, instead of the default value, which is <codeph>eucalyptus</codeph>. For example, if this value is set to <codeph>foobar</codeph>, the instance DNS names will appear as <codeph>euca-A.B.C.D.foobar.&lt;subdomain></codeph>.</p>
					</info>
				</step>
			</steps>
		</taskbody>
	</task>
	<task outputclass="docs one-sidebar sidebar-first" id="setting_up_dns_del">
		<title>Enable DNS Delegation</title>
		<taskbody>
			<context>
				<note type="restriction">If you are not using HA, you can skip this task.</note>
				<p>DNS delegation allows you to forward DNS traffic for the Eucalyptus subdomain to the
					Eucalyptus CLC hosts. These hosts act as name servers. This allows interruption-free access to
					Eucalyptus cloud services in the event of a failure. Both primary and secondary CLC hosts are
					capable of mapping cloud host names to IP addresses of the primary CLC and Walrus hosts.</p>
				<p>For example, if the IP address of the primary and secondary CLC are
					<codeph>192.168.5.1</codeph> and <codeph>192.168.5.2</codeph>, and the IP addresses of
					primary and secondary Walruses are <codeph>192.168.6.1</codeph> and <codeph>192.168.6.2</codeph>, the host <codeph>eucalyptus.eucadomain.yourdomain</codeph> will resolve to <codeph>192.168.6.1</codeph> and <codeph>walrus.eucadomain.yourdomain</codeph> will resolve to <codeph>192.168.6.1</codeph>.</p>
				<p>If the primary CLC fails, the secondary CLC will become the primary and
					<codeph>eucalyptus.eucadomain.yourdomain</codeph> will resolve to
					<codeph>192.168.5.2</codeph>. If the primary Walrus fails, the secondary Walrus will be promoted and <codeph>walrus.eucadomain.yourdomain</codeph> will resolve to <codeph>192.168.6.2</codeph>.</p>
				<p>To enable DNS delegation:</p>
				
			</context>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<cmd>On the primary CLC, enter the following command:</cmd>
					<info>
						<codeblock>euca-modify-property -p bootstrap.webservices.use_dns_delegation=true</codeblock>
						
					</info>
				</step>
				<step>
					<cmd>Because the credentials are now slightly changed, you must generate the administrative
						credentials and source the <filepath>eucarc</filepath> file again. For more information, see
						<xref href="../ig/admin_creds.dita"/>.</cmd>
					
				</step>
			</steps>
		</taskbody>
	</task>
	<task outputclass="docs one-sidebar sidebar-first" id="setting_up_dns_master">
		<title>Configure the Master DNS Server</title>
		<taskbody>
			<context>
				<p>Set up your master DNS server to forward the Eucalyptus subdomain to the primary and secondary CLC servers, which act as name servers.</p>
				<p>The following example shows how the Linux name server <codeph>bind</codeph> is set up to
					forward the Eucalyptus subdomain.</p>
				
				
			</context>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<cmd>Open <filepath>/etc/named.conf</filepath> and set up the <codeph>eucadomain.yourdomain
					zone</codeph>. For example, your <filepath>/etc/named.conf</filepath> may look like the
					following:</cmd>
					<info>
						<codeblock>zone "yourdomain" {
type master;
file "/etc/bind/db.yourdomain";
};

#Forward eucadomain.yourdomain
zone "eucadomain.yourdomain" {
type forward;
forward only;
forwarders { &lt;CLC_0_IP>; &lt;CLC_1_IP>; };
};</codeblock>
						<p>where <codeph>&lt;CLC_0_IP></codeph> is the IP address of your primary CLC and
							<codeph>&lt;CLC_1_IP></codeph> is the IP address of your secondary CLC.</p>
					</info>
				</step>
				<step>
					<cmd>Create <filepath>/etc/bind/db.yourdomain</filepath> if it does not exist. If your master
						DNS is already set up for <codeph>yourdomain</codeph>, you will need to add name server
						entries for <codeph>&lt;CLC_0_IP></codeph> and <codeph>&lt;CLC_1_IP></codeph>. For example:</cmd>
					<info>
						<codeblock>$TTL 604800
@ IN SOA yourdomain. root.yourdomain. (
2 ; Serial
604800 ; Refresh
86400 ; Retry
2419200 ; Expire
604800 ) ; Negative Cache TTL
;
@ IN NS ns.yourdomain.
@ IN A &lt;master_nameserver_IP>
			
ns.yourdomain. IN A &lt;master_nameserver_IP>
				
;Add entries for primary and secondary CLCs 
eucadomain.yourdomain. IN NS clc0.eucadomain.yourdomain.
eucadomain.yourdomain. IN NS clc1.eucadomain.yourdomain.
				
clc0.eucadomain.yourdomain. IN A &lt;CLC_0_IP>
clc1.eucadomain.yourdomain. IN A &lt;CLC_1_IP></codeblock>
						<p>where <codeph>clc0.eucadomain.yourdomain</codeph> and <codeph>clc1.eucadomain.yourdomain</codeph> are the host names of your primary and secondary CLC servers.</p>
					</info>
				</step>
				<step>
					<cmd>Restart the bind nameserver (<codeph>/etc/init.d/bind9 restart</codeph> or
						<codeph>/etc/init.d/named restart</codeph>, depending on your Linux distribution).</cmd>
				</step>
				<step>
					<cmd>Test your setup by pointing <codeph>/etc/resolv.conf</codeph> on your client to your
						primary DNS server and attempt to resolve <codeph>eucalyptus.eucadomain.yourdomain</codeph>
						using ping or nslookup. It should return the IP address of the primary CLC server.</cmd>
				</step>
			</steps>
		</taskbody>
	</task>
</task>
