<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_bkz_gyc_12">
 <title>Clusters</title>
 <conbody>
  <p>An cluster is a subset of the cloud (typically a collection of servers and storage) that shares
   a local area network and are in the same network broadcast domain. A cluster offers a fixed
   amount of resources to the cloud, and access to those resources can be controlled via quotas and
   access control lists.  It is a best practice to configure a cluster with server hardware that has
   the same, or very similar, performance capabilities.  This ensures that the cluster offers the
   same performance capabilities to all instances that are run in the cluster.</p>
  <p>A cluster is the Eucalyptus implementation of an Amazon Availability Zone. A cluster could be a
   single point of failure. Configuring multiple clusters and deploying an application across them
   increases the availability of the application. </p>
  <p>A cluster is also sometimes referred to as a partition. Many Eucalyptus users use the terms
   cluster, availability zone, and partition interchangeably. </p>
  <p/>
  <image href="images/Cluster-Illustration.png" placement="break" id="image_3dj_gjm_f3" scale="60"/>
  <p/>
  <p>Multiple clusters can be deployed for administrative or technical reasons. </p>
  <p>Administrative separations happen due to resource ownership (for example, the Engineering group
   owns a collection of servers, therefore they get exclusive access to them in the cloud) or
   compliance purposes (when certain data is legally not allowed to exist in certain places). </p>
  <p>Technical separations happen when you want, for example, to provide different service level
   agreements (SLAs) to different users in the same cloud.  Different clusters can be deployed with
   hardware with different performance capabilities. As such, the SLAs offered to instances running
   in different clusters can vary.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
