<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept outputclass="docs one-sidebar sidebar-first" id="planning_vmware">
 <title>VMware Support</title>
 <shortdesc></shortdesc>
 <conbody>
		<p>Eucalyptus includes an optional subscription-only component, the VMware Broker. The
			VMware Broker mediates all interaction between Eucalyptus and VMware infrastructure
			components (that is, ESX/ESXi, and vCenter). In the following diagram VB is controlling
			VMware infrastructure through a vCenter server, but it can also connect to ESX/ESXi
			hosts directly, without vCenter server present.</p>
 	<image href="../shared/images/euca-arch-basic-vcenter-cluster.png"/>
 	<p>Eucalyptus provides:</p>
 	<ul>
 	<li>Support for VMware vSphere infrastructure as the platform for deploying virtual machines</li>
 	<li>The ability to extend cloud-based features (for example, elastic IPs, security groups, Amazon S3, etc.) to a VMware infrastructure</li>
 	<li>Compatibility with VMware vSphere client, which can be used alongside Eucalyptus</li>	
 	</ul>
 	<p>The VMware Broker can run with either an administrative account or a minimally-privileged account on the VMware host. </p>
 	
 	<section>
 		<title>VMware Support Prerequisites</title>
 		
 		<p>If you plan to use Eucalyptus with VMware, there are some additional prerequisites:</p>
 		<ul>
 		<li>You must install and configure the VMware infrastructure software (ESX and/or ESXi hypervisors with or without vCenter server).</li>
 		<li>The CC server (that will also run the VMware Broker) must be able to route network traffic to
					and from the physical servers running VMware software on ports 443, 902, and
					903. If there are internal firewalls present, these firewalls must be configured
					to open these ports so that the Eucalyptus cloud components can communicate
					with the VMware services and hypervisors.</li>
 		<li>You must provide the VMware administrator account credentials to Eucalyptus when you
					configure VMware support, or an equivalent account with sufficient permissions
					must be created on VMware vCenter or ESX hosts. See "Configuring VMware" section for more details.</li>
 		</ul>
			<p>For additional information on VMware support for Eucalyptus, contact Eucalyptus
				Systems, Inc.</p>
 		
 	</section>
 	
 </conbody>
</concept>
