<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept outputclass="docs one-sidebar sidebar-first" id="planning_ha">
 <title>High Availability Support</title>
 <shortdesc></shortdesc>
 <conbody>
 	<p>Eucalyptus includes the ability to run redundant, hot swappable instances for the CLC, Walrus, CC, SC, and VMware Broker components. In a high availability (HA) configuration, a failure of any single component will not cause the system to halt. If your network configuration includes redundant networking hardware and routing paths, HA Eucalyptus can then tolerate a network component failure (e.g. the loss of a networking switch) without halting.</p>
 	<p>The deployment choices for HA Eucalyptus are similar to a regular Eucalyptus deployment, with
 		the following additional considerations:</p>
 	<ul><li>You must host redundant Eucalyptus software components on separate hardware components in order to be able to tolerate a hardware failure. If, for example, you install redundant CLCs on the same machine and the machine crashes, both CLCs will become inoperable. </li>
 	<li>The redundant components occur in pairs, one primary, the other secondary. These components must be able to communicate with each
 		other through the network to which they are both attached while they are running. For example, both CLC components in an HA installation must be able to exchange messages. If you use a firewall to separate them, one will not detect a failure of the other and a hot failover will not occur. This ability for pairs of components to communicate is required for the CLC, Walrus, CC, SC, and the VMware Broker for HA to operate properly.</li></ul> 
 	
 	<p>The following images shows a single cluster deployment with the component pairs at the cloud
 		and cluster level. The NCs are not redundant.</p>
 	<image href="../shared/images/euca-arch-ha-one-cluster.png"/>
 <p>Note that the same considerations for a regular Eucalyptus deployment with respect to networking mode and
 	components placement apply to HA Eucalyptus in addition to the need for redundant component pairs
 	to be able to communicate. Note also that the NC components are deployed redundantly in an HA
 	Eucalyptus deployment. If a machine running an NC fails, Eucalyptus will continue to be available for
 	user requests. However, instances running on that specific NC will be lost.</p>
 	
 	<note type="restriction">The installation and configuration sections will note instructions
 		specific to HA deployment by the HA icon.</note>
 	
 </conbody>
</concept>
