<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="security_bp_access">
  <title> Authentication and Access Control</title>
	<shortdesc>This topic describes best practices for Identity and Access Management and the <codeph>eucalyptus</codeph>
		account.</shortdesc>
  <conbody>
    <section>
    	<title>Identity and Access Management</title>
      <p>Eucalyptus manages access control through an authentication,
        authorization, and accounting system. This system manages user
        identities, enforces access controls over resources, and provides
        reporting on resource usage as a basis for auditing and managing cloud
        activities. The user identity organizational model and the scheme of
        authorizations used to access resources are based on and compatible with
        the AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) system, with some
        Eucalyptus extensions provided that support ease-of-use in a private
        cloud environment.</p>
      <p>For a general introduction to IAM in Eucalyptus, see <xref
          href="../admin-guide/concepts_eiam.dita"/> in the Administration Guide. For information
        about using IAM quotas to enforce limits on resource usage by users and
        accounts in Eucalyptus, see the <xref
          href="../admin-guide/access_policy_quota.dita"/> section in the Administration Guide.</p>
      <p>The <xref
          href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/IAMBestPractices.html"
          scope="external" format="html">Amazon Web Services IAM Best Practices</xref> are also
        generally applicable to Eucalyptus.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Credential Management</title>
      <p>Only create users and credentials for the interfaces that you will
        actually use. For example, if you're only going to use an account
        through the Management Console, do not create credentials for the SOAP and
        Query interfaces.</p>
    	<p>Using <codeph>euca_conf --get-credentials</codeph> creates a new set of X.509 certificates on each request.  Use <codeph>euare-useraddkey</codeph> and <codeph>euare-usercreatecert</codeph> to get a specific set of credentials whenever possible.</p>
    	<p>When rotating credentials, there is an option to deactivate, instead of removing, existing
    		access/secret keys and X.509 certificates. Requests made using deactivated credentials will no
    		longer be accepted, but the credentials will remain in the Eucalyptus database and can be
    		restored if needed. You can deactive credentials using <codeph>euare-usermodkey</codeph> and <codeph>euare-usermodcert</codeph>.</p>
    </section>
  </conbody>
	<!--<related-links>
		<link><desc></desc></link>
	</related-links>-->
</concept>
