<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="manage_volume_ui_context">
    <title>Manage Volumes</title>
    <shortdesc> Eucalyptus offers persistent storage that you can attach to a running instance.
        These Eucalyptus block storage (EBS) volumes persist autonomously from the running life of
        an instance. After you attach a block volume to an instance, you can use it like any other
        physical hard drive. This screen allows you to view a list of your volumes, create new
        volumes, and delete volumes. You can page through the list of volumes by clicking the
        navigation buttons at the bottom of the screen. </shortdesc>
    <taskbody/>
    <task id="manage_volume_ui_sorting_steps">
        <title>Sorting the Volume List</title>
        <shortdesc/>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>Click on any column header to toggle sorting the list of volumes in
                        ascending or descending order by the selected column.</cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="manage_volume_ui_searching_steps">
        <title>Searching the Volume List</title>
        <shortdesc/>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>Type some search text into the <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> text box to
                        filter the list of volumes. </cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="manage_volume_ui_create_steps">
        <title>Creating a Volume</title>
        <shortdesc/>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Create new volume</uicontrol> button. The Create
                        Volume dialog box will appear.</cmd>
                </step>

            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="manage_volume_ui_attach_steps">
        <title>Attach a Volume to a Running Instance</title>
        <shortdesc/>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>Right-click on the unattached volume you wish to attach to a running
                        instance.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> Select <uicontrol>Attach to instance</uicontrol> from the context menu.
                        The <uicontrol>Attach volume to instance</uicontrol> dialog box will appear.
                    </cmd>
                    <info>
                        <note>You can also click on a volume and click the <uicontrol>More
                            actions</uicontrol> link at the top of the list.</note>
                    </info>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="manage_volume_ui_detach_steps">
        <title>Detach a Volume from a Running Instance</title>
        <shortdesc/>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>Right-click on the attached volume you wish to detach from a running
                        instance.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> Select <uicontrol>Detach from instance</uicontrol> from the context menu.
                        The <uicontrol>Detach volume to instance</uicontrol> dialog box will appear. </cmd>
                    <info>
                        <note>You can also click on a volume and click the <uicontrol>More
                                actions</uicontrol> link at the top of the list.</note>
                    </info>
                </step>

            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="manage_volume_ui_snapshot_steps">
        <title>Create a Snapshot from a Volume</title>
        <shortdesc/>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>Right-click on the volume that you wish to use as the source of a new
                        snapshot.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> Select <uicontrol>Create snapshot from volume</uicontrol> from the context
                        menu. The <uicontrol>Create snapshot from volume</uicontrol> dialog box will
                        appear. </cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
    <task id="manage_volume_ui_delete_steps">
        <title>Deleting Volumes</title>
        <shortdesc/>
        <taskbody>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <cmd>Click the checkbox next to the volume.</cmd>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <cmd> Right-click in the volume list and select <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>
                        from the context menu. The <uicontrol>Delete Volume</uicontrol> dialog box
                        will appear. </cmd>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </taskbody>
    </task>
</task>
