<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--This work by Eucalyptus Systems is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. See the accompanying LICENSE file for more information.-->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_h1h_2tx_3f">
 <title>Create a New Image from Installation Media</title>
 <conbody>
  <p>To create a brand-new image from installation media is a time-consuming, multi-step, and
            potentially error-prone process. One of the ways to accomplish this is to log in to the
            Node Controller and manually create a virtual machine using KVM or libvirt utilities.  
            The virtual machine should have a virtual disk file large enough to hold the operating
            system and any applications you plan on installing.   Once the virtual machine exists,
            use installation media to install the operating system and any applications on the
            virtual disk.  The virtual disk will actually be a <filepath>.img</filepath> file on the
            Node Controller. </p>
        <p/>
        <p>
            <image href="images/Create-From-Installation-Media.png" placement="break"
                id="image_qpx_xzl_h3" scale="55"/>
        </p>
        <p/>
        <p>Once you have a virtual machine disk file (an <filepath>.img</filepath> file), you will
            still need modify the image file before you bundle, upload, and register the image.
            Unfortunately, errors that occur early in the image creation process can go undetected
            until a user tries to use the image to launch a new instance. For more information about
            manually creating new image files, see the <i>Eucalyptus User Guide</i> at <xref
                href="https://www.eucalyptus.comdocs" format="html" scope="external"
                >http://www.eucalyptus.com/docs</xref>.</p>
        <p>Because this method can be time-consuming, software tools exist and are being developed
            that are designed to build images for you and remove some of the possibility of human
            error. <note>Examples of such tools include AMI Creator (<xref
                    href="https://github.com/katzj/ami-creator" format="html" scope="external"
                    >https://github.com/katzj/ami-creator</xref>), BoxGrinder (<xref
                    href="http://boxgrinder.org" format="html" scope="external"
                    >http://boxgrinder.org</xref>) and UForge (<xref
                    href="http://www.usharesoft.com" format="html" scope="external"
                    >http://www.usharesoft.com</xref>).</note></p>
  <p>In order to simplify image creation and management in the cloud, many administrators will
            provide users with basic, known working images and allow them to modify these existing
            images to create new ones. This is often a simpler and faster approach.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
