<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_x4d_2kb_12">
 <title>SYSTEM Mode</title>
 <conbody>
  <p>SYSTEM is the default network mode for Eucalyptus clouds. It assumes that virtual machine
      instances will be assigned IP addresses by an external DHCP server. </p>
  <p>Eucalyptus clouds in SYSTEM mode also do not support the use of elastic IP addresses, security
      groups, or the further isolation instances in different security groups by placing them in
      separate VLANs. Both security groups and elastic IP addresses are discussed in more detail in
      other sections of this training module.</p>
    <p/>
  <image href="images/System-Feature-Summary.png" placement="break" id="image_2rh_j41_2f" scale="45"/>
    <p><sup>1</sup>An elastic IP address is a public IP address that the user reserves and manually
      assigns to their instance.</p>
    <p><sup>2</sup>A security group is a set of firewall rules applied to all instances that are
      members of the security group. </p>
    <p/>
    <p>SYSTEM mode is most often used in setting up test or proof-of-concepts (POCs) environments.
      It is seldom used in production environments. SYSTEM mode is the least intrusive network mode
      in that it often requires no substantial changes to the existing datacenter network.</p>
  <p>Instances receive a single IP address from the organization's DHCP server. All instances have
      direct network access through the network bridge in the Node Controller, and will thus appear
      as though they are physical machines on the network. You must ensure that a bridge is
      configured on each Node Controller prior to installing the Eucalyptus software. It is up to
      the IT administration team to provide and manage any additional network functionality like
      network firewalls or network address translation.</p>
    <p/>
  <p>
      <image href="images/System-Mode-Logical-View.png" placement="break" id="image_4fh_sck_1h"
        scale="45"/>
    </p>
    <p/>
    <p/>
  <p>The following is an example of what a physical layout might look like for a Eucalyptus cloud
      configured in SYSTEM mode. In this example, the front-end server, Node Controllers, and all
      virtual machine instances have IP addresses on the 173.205.188.0/24 network.</p>
    <p/>
    <p>
      <image href="images/System-Mode-Physical-View.png" placement="break" id="image_2n5_tp1_2f"
        scale="55"/>
    </p>
    <p/>
  <p>The requirements for SYSTEM mode are:<ul id="ul_22p_xp1_2f">
    <li>A pre-existing DHCP server on the network</li>
    <li>A range of IP addresses available for use by Eucalyptus hosts and instances</li>
    <li>The Ethernet interfaces on the Node Controllers that communicates with the Cluster
          Controller must be bridged before installing the Eucalyptus software.</li>
   </ul></p>
 </conbody>
</concept>
